What we recommend you to do is user
interviews.
So, questions you ask your users. These
will be actual discussions that you have
with users. And that's a research method
used during the discovery phase
where the interviewer ask participants
questions about a specific topic.
And they show you who they are and what
they do. Not only do you like my product
because that's not the question you
should ask, but to understand what their
life is.
Just to give you an example,
if you're building for construction site
workers, guess what? You'll need
to talk to construction site workers
to see how they work. The best
interviews are 90% listening and only
10% talking. And they're not informal.
They shouldn't be informal. They should
be written down with a guide
and whatever I will tell you now. So,
you need to identify what you would like
to learn. At the beginning, you will do
something that we call exploratory
interviews because you're not doing
interviews on a specific specific topic.
At the beginning, we you should go to
validate the whole problem space and
deep dive into those users that you
think are your users. You should prepare
a guide and we're going to discuss a bit
about that. You should pilot that that
guide.
And
pilot, I mean
talk to someone in an interview session
that would be more friendly.
And at the beginning, you should start
easy, build rapport. What that means is
that if you haven't done interviews
until now with users, you're going to
see that you can't just go there and
start asking your questions and then
leave and expect that everything goes
smoothly because human interactions
don't look like that. This sort of
interviews should be recorded. You
should have a colleague that is
with you to write notes.
And you should have the questions
written down.
Social cues that I will mention and
maybe these are things that you can also
use moving forward also in mentoring.
You should make eye contact. Guess what?
That is important to make eye contact.
You should not
So, whenever someone talks to you and
you want to interview them, so you want
them to feel comfortable telling you
different things and answering to your
questions because guess what? People
tend to not answer your questions openly
if you are not friendly.
>> [snorts]
>> Um, you should do this nodding so that
you approve what they say. Even though
they might not be right, but if you nod
um,
they will get the feeling that you are
listening to them, you are paying
attention and you agree and they can
move forward. So, it's a confirmation.
You should mirror them. Mirroring is
something that maybe we do
unconsciously, but you should do
consciously because in this sort of
interviews, maybe in the first 100 that
you do, you won't feel that comfortable
doing stuff. Mirroring is for example,
if they drink water, you drink water.
Because you saw that they drink water.
If they nod, you nod and so on. So, this
sort of mirroring works also maybe in
dating if you do that. So, if you think
about it that's a fun fact to know.
Echoing
What echoing means, it means when they
say something like a sentence, you
repeat the last words of the sentence.
It's quite helpful. People actually
appreciate that because they see that
you paid attention to what they said. Or
at least that's what they understand
through so that social cue. And
approval. You say, "Yes, yes, I
understand. That's great. Sure. Wow,
that's how it works."
So that they
um
build up on it because you need info.
You need them talking 90% of the time.
You need all of their problems on the
table so that they talk and talk to you
so that you discover more and more about
the problem that you are trying to
solve.